Joshua Senyi-Philips

philipsjoshua96@gmail.com +233559059563 / +233209120905 Accra, Ghana

Summary

BSc. in Computer Engineering graduate, with a particular interest in software development. Very energetic with excellent interpersonal and communication abilities, along with a wide range of technical skills.

Online

joshua-philips.github.io

Skills

Mobile App Development (Flutter), Mobile UI/UX Design, Front-End Development, Backend Development (Java), Wireframing, Software Documentation, Prototyping, Research & Development, Client Services

Languages & Tools

- Java, JavaFX, Flutter, Dart, Firebase, MySql, Git
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React
- · Spring Boot, Maven
- VSCode, Eclipse, Android Studio, Scenebuilder
- · Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Figma, Artboard Studio, Github
- Microsoft Office (Excel, Access, Word, PowerPoint, Publisher)

Education

B.Sc Computer Engineering

Ghana Technology University College Graduated - 11/2019

Graduated with second class upper division (CWA 66.03). Recipient of the Barclays Tertiary Scholarship from the 2017/2018 academic year until graduation in 2019.

WASSCE (General Science-Elective ICT)

Adisadel College Graduated - 05/2014

Employment History

Mobile App Developer

Filly Coder Limited • Accra, Greater Accra Region

11/2021 - Present

• Working remotely with UI designers and other Mobile and Web developers to create cross platform mobile applications using Flutter and Firebase along with other other related tools.

•

IT Support/Client Service Officer (National Service)

Nursing and Midwifery Council of Ghana • Accra, Greater Accra Region 09/2019 - 08/2020

- Responsible for maintaining computer systems as well as troubleshooting and fixing network and system
 problems.
- Part of the team responsible for issuing/renewing nursing licenses and providing other company services to clients.

Intern

Phalcon Technologies Ghana • Greater Accra Region 06/2018 - 09/2018

Worked mainly as an administrative assistant, writing up outgoing project proposals for the startup.

Personal Projects

- <u>Yarisa Healthcare UI</u>: A healthcare mobile app for connecting patients, doctors and health facilities. I was responsible for designing the screens of the app. The goal for the design was to keep in line with current iOS and Android trends while considering the target audience.
- Read Log Mobile App: A Flutter app for Android and iOS for tracking a user's books.
- Cedi Budget: Mobile app built with Flutter and Firebase to track budget and expenditure

References Available On Request